<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE script:module PUBLIC "-//OpenOffice.org//DTD OfficeDocument 1.0//EN" "module.dtd">
<script:module xmlns:script="http://openoffice.org/2000/script" script:name="z_ToDo" script:language="StarBasic">&apos; The To Do List....
Sub Main

End Sub

&apos; ***GENERAL***
&apos;
&apos;	-Update the ReadMe to have a basic &quot;How to Use&quot; section for the spreadsheet that at least talks about the Yellow and Orange areas.
&apos;		Possibly a simple one- or two-turn walkthrough.
&apos;
&apos;   -make saving versions an option and add an option to create a new version backup at save time instead/as well.
&apos;   	For the save file option, don&apos;t bother with a &quot;save as&quot; because of the context issue; 
&apos;			save the current file and then use an O/S level copy to backup the file.
&apos;

&apos; ***Customization and data***
&apos;	-currently there is skill color customization on *both* the skills tab and the posting templates tab...reconcile that
&apos;
&apos;	-allow customization of agendas if the table doesn&apos;t like one or more of the included ones? 
&apos;
&apos;	-7 player support without a cylon leader?
&apos;
&apos;	-Allow customization of crisis deck by mix of card type?
&apos;
&apos;	-add validations for the Destination and Quorum deck like we have for skills and crisis?

&apos; ***GAME STATE***


&apos; ***SETUP***
&apos; -add place for the game NAME/NUMBER (used for the imamge generation)
&apos;
&apos; -add area for the GIMP file prep which would verify the available paths &amp; files 
&apos;		(both for gimp and for the master.xcf file?) and potentially create the new game master .xcf file?
&apos;
&apos; -available characters should be pulled from Reference


&apos; ***LOYALTY***
&apos; -pull Agendas from Reference?
&apos; -pull all loyalty cards from Reference?


&apos; ***SKILL***
&apos;
&apos; Skill Check management to be more formal
&apos;   -Essentially need to have three states:
&apos;		*CLEAR* - no skill check in play, skill check can be invoked, either from crisis tab or skill tab.
&apos;		*PREP/INT* - skill check has been invoked.  Interrupts can be played here (only).
&apos;		*IN PROGRESS* - no more interrupts, destiny has been added (unless guts played).  can play into check or clear the check.
&apos;
&apos; -Support Exodus skill = 0 cards


&apos; ***POSTING TEMPLATES***


&apos; ***DESTINATION***
&apos; 	-add support for Gas Cloud (crisis reorder?)
&apos;
&apos;	-add support for Mining Asteroid (in terms of invoking Scar).


&apos; ***SHIPS***

&apos; ***CRISIS***

&apos; ***IMAGE DATA***
&apos; - currently lots of data is pulled from Board Status....probably we should be going against primary sources


&apos; ***IMAGE (GIMP)***
&apos;	- revisit the default locations of scar and the pilots, they appear to overlap in some cases.
&apos;
&apos;	- enhance the graveyard to include ships (civilians, raptors, vipers)
&apos;
&apos; 	- support moving the character bar to the top or bottom?


&apos; ***REFERENCE***

&apos; ***EXODUS: Ionian Nebula***
&apos; - Crossroads Phase: Elimination is not currently supported (eliminate a player so he shows up blank on the image and turn will skip him)
&apos;


&apos; ***EXODUS: Cylon Fleet***
&apos; - Add GIMP support for Pegasus + Cylon Fleet + New Caprica
&apos;		GIMP is supported...now investigate what happens when Galactica Returns and there are ships on the Cylon Fleet

&apos; ***EXODUS: Conflicted Loyalties***

&apos; ***REPORTED BUGS***
&apos; per Jasperhawk - problem with two charcaters in a two-word location?  I can&apos;t reproduce, keep investigating.

</script:module>